# Connor Gramazio

PhD Candidate, Computer Science

My research aims to simplify the visualization of complex cancer genomics data through the development of novel visualization techniques. To create meaningful innovation for cancer visual analysis it is imperative to not just create new computational techniques, but to also understand how scientists incorporate visual analysis into their workflows. To that end, my research draws on both quantitative and qualitative methods to inform system development and algorithm design. My long-term goal is to create recommender systems that simplify the design of complex visualizations using knowledge from data visualization, human-computer interaction, and visual perception.

# **Education**

2012-now Ph.D Computer Science Brown University

Advisor: David H. Laidlaw

2012-2014 **Sc.M** Computer Science **Brown University** 

Thesis: The relation between visualization size, grouping, and user performance

B.S. Computer Science Minor Religion, Cum laude with highest thesis honors. 2008-2012 Tufts University

Thesis: Optimizing an SPT-tree for visual analytics

Advisors: Remco Chang, Ben Hescott

# **Experience**

2012-now **Brown University: Graduate Researcher** 

> Lead integrative, multidisciplinary visualization research by combining topics in cancer genomics, data visualization, and visual perception. Research involved both large-team and single-person research & development efforts. Honed qualitative and quantitative evaluation as well as statistical analysis skills. Collaborated with Professors Ben Raphael (computational biology), Karen Schloss (psychology), and Jeff Huang (HCI).

2012 **Google: Software Engineer Intern** 

> Independently designed and implemented full-stack feature for Ripples, a Google+ content discovery visualization. Involved paper prototyping, UI/UX design, Java asynchornous middleware programming, C++ BigTable queries, Javascript visualization programming, and designing for data center resource constraints.

2010-2012 **Tufts University: Undergraduate Researcher** 

> Pursued independent visualization research in protein structure rendering, Java heap static analysis, and visual analytics. Research spanned user studies, visualization programming, and algorithm design.

2011 Charles River Analytics: Software Engineer/Scientist Intern

> Independently paper prototyped and implemented environment for controlling multiple, heterogeneous unmanned vehicles in Java/Swing. Designed a user study to test visualization techniques for managing tem-

poral constraints in emergency disaster response.

# **Teaching**

2015 **Teaching Certificate I, Sheridan Center, Brown University** 

Refined skills in reflective teaching practices and effective communication.

2015 **Guest lecturer: Data Visualization, Tufts University** 

Gave lecture on the role of visual perception and color in effective visualization design.

2010 **Head Teaching Assistant: Computer Graphics, Tufts University** 

Co-created course material and homework assignments, graded, and held additional office hours.

2010-2011 **Teaching Assistant: Data Structure, Tufts University** 

Taught introductory-level computer science labs and held additional office hours.

# **Awards**

2012-2016	NSF Graduate Research Fellowship
2012-2013	Andries van Dam Graduate Fellowship

2011 Computer Research Association Outstanding Undergraduate Research Award, Honorable Mention

2011 de Florez Prize in Human Engineering

2010 Dean of Engineering Scholar, Tufts' Summer Scholars

2010-2012 Tufts' Cape Cod Club Scholarship

2009-2010 Computer Science, Engineering, and Math Scholars Scholarship

# **Publications**

#### **Peer-reviewed Publications**

### MAGI: visualization and collaborative annotation of genomic aberrations

Mark D.M. Leiserson, Connor C. Gramazio, Jason Hu, Hsin-Ta Wu, David H. Laidlaw, Benjamin J. Raphael Nature Methods 12.6 (June 2015) pp. 483–484. Nature Publishing Group, 2015

#### Exploring hierarchical visualization designs using phylogenetic trees

Shaomeng Li, R. Jordan Crouser, Garth Griffin, Connor C. Gramazio, Hans-Jörg Schulz, Hank Childs, Remco Chang Proc. SPIE 9397 (2015) pages. 2015

# Crowdsourcing from Scratch: A Pragmatic Experiment in Data Collection by Novice Requesters

Alexandra Papoutsaki, Hua Guo, Danae Metaxa-Kakavouli, Connor C. Gramazio, Jeff Rasley, Wenting Xie, Guan Wang, Jeff Huang Proceedings of The AAAI Conference on Human Computation and Crowdsourcing (HCOMP) (2015). 2015

### The relation between visualization size, grouping, and user performance

Connor C. Gramazio, Karen B. Schloss, David H. Laidlaw

IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics/VIS 2014 20.12 (Dec. 2014) pp. 1953-1962. 2014

#### Heapviz: Interactive heap visualization for program understanding and debugging (Extended)

Sean Kelley, Edward Aftandilian, Connor Gramazio, Nathan Ricci, Sara L. Su, Samuel Z. Guyer Information Visualization 12.2 (2013) pp. 163–177. 2013

#### Molli: Interactive Visualization for Exploratory Protein Analysis

S. Su, C. Gramazio, D. Extrum-Fernandez, C. Crumm, L.J. Cowen, M. Menke, M. Strait Computer Graphics and Applications, IEEE 32.5 (Sept. 2012) pp. 62–69. 2012

#### Heapviz: Interactive Heap Visualization for Program Understanding and Debugging

Edward E. Aftandilian, Sean Kelley, Connor Gramazio, Nathan Ricci, Sara L. Su, Samuel Z. Guyer Proceedings of the 5th International Symposium on Software Visualization (2010) pp. 53–62. ACM, 2010

#### **Conference Abstracts, Demos, & Posters**

#### Which color means more? An investigation of color-quantity mapping in data visualization

Karen B. Schloss, Connor C. Gramazio, Charlotte Walmsley *Journal of vision/VSS*, 2015

#### Cancer Genome Analysis Tool (CGAT) for the Visualization and Exploration of Combinations of Mutations in Cancer

Mark D.M. Leiserson, Hsin-Ta Wu, Connor C. Gramazio, Benjamin J. Raphael

The 4th Annual The Cancer Genome Atlas Symposium, 2014

#### MAGI: A Platform for Interactive Visualization and Collaborative Annotation of Combinations of Genetic Aberrations

Mark Leiserson, Hsin-Ta Wu, Connor Gramazio, Benjamin Raphael

The 1st Biological Data Science Meeting, 2014

#### Optimizing an spt-tree for visual analytics

Connor Gramazio, Remco Chang

IEEE Conference on Visual Analytics Science and Technology (VAST), 2012

### Moleint: Reducing Workload through Adaptive Interaction

Megan Strait, Connor Gramazio, Jisoo Park, Sara L. Su, Lenore Cowen

VIZBI, 2012

### An analytical approach for the creative design of new visualizations

Garth Griffin, Shaomeng Li, Connor Gramazio, Remco Chang *IEEE Conference on Information Visualization (InfoVis)*, 2011

# Heapviz: A Programmer's Tool for Data Structure Visualization

Edward E. Aftandilian, Sean Kelley, Connor Gramazio, Nathan Ricci, Sara L. Su, Samuel Z. Guyer *IEEE VisWeek Demo*, 2010

## TuftsViewer: An intuitive interface for viewing 3D protein structures

Menke Matt, Sara L. Su, Connor Gramazio, Caitlin Crumm, Daniela Extrum-Fernandez, Lenore Cowen 3DSIG Workshop at ISMB, 2010

Programming
JavaScript, Python
C, Java
HTML5/CSS3, LATEX

**Design**Adobe Illustrator
Adobe Photoshop
Paper prototyping

**Statistics** R, SPSS

**Frameworks/Libraries** d3, ggplot, numpy, Tornado, node.js, git